Double-click on HANA to open it.
Double-click on the GAMUT folder to add a new casual outfit.
Double-click on the
to add a new scarf.
Then increase the particle diameter of all selected panels to 15
Since the panels are small, if the particle diameter is increased, the number of panels will decrease, and it will look stiff.
Select all panels, choose freeze, so that all costumes will no longer participate in the simulation
But it will still clash with the newly created scarf panels
Move all panels in the 2D window to prevent the panels from overlapping, and you can see the model screenshot for reference
Then draw a rectangle that can almost cover the model's face, the length and the length of the hands are almost the same
This width and length can be decided by yourself
The scarf is arranged at the back of the virtual model
Because the center of the scarf is usually located in the back of the scarf
Adjust the structure of the arrangement
Make the scarf the innermost part of the scarf
Don't have a gap between the model and the scarf
This makes the scarf more stable
The part where the image and the costume have a gap can be temporarily ignored
Because it will make the scarf narrower later
Use the edit texture tool to click a panel
You can see the direction of the panel's brush stroke
The arrow direction refers to the shape of the cloth
All the shape numbers in the software are in this direction
By modifying the shape reduction, you can make the panel more stable
In the simulation, the image is temporarily shrinked to 30% of the original size
When you start the simulation, you can see that the scarf is narrower
This is the function of the shrink
When pulling the scarf, usually pull one end first
When you see that there is a clear deformation, you know that you can add a fixing pin to fix it
When modeling, press the W key and click the board to increase the fixing pin
After fixing one end, pull the other end
Remember to see if there is a penetrating part in the process
And remember to check if there is a part of the hair that is accidentally hung
Sometimes there are many small gaps in the hair
It is easy to hang a larger version of the grid
After wearing and stabilizing
The shrink rate will gradually increase to 60%
Do not directly increase a lot
Otherwise it will be unstable easily
Then manually adjust the wrinkle shape
After finishing, select the scarf fabric
And under the detail attribute in the attribute editor
Increase the friction rate to prevent the scarf from sliding
After finishing, select the scarf fabric
If you want to tie the scarf, you have to add a fixing pin at both ends first
Then drag the fixing pin to cross the scarf
Add a fixing pin at the intersection
This can fix the knot
Add another fixing pin
Let the scarf have extra space below the scarf to wear the scarf
Then drag the fixing pin to one end
Let the scarf pass through the gap in the middle
Here it is recommended to open the pressure chart on the left side
When the pressure turns red
It shows that the scarf has changed very much
Try to avoid continuing to stretch
Because of the increased friction rate
The scarf is not easy to penetrate each other at this time
So pull a fixing pin
Then wait for the scarf to tighten a little
After that, you can delete the fixing pin used to fix the intersection
Then continue to pull the fixing pin
Let the scarf tighten slowly
If the friction rate is relatively low
You can see that it tightens very quickly
This is more likely to cause instability
It is recommended to maintain the friction rate of 15
When adjusting the length of the scarf
Please select the two ends of the line and then move
Or you can use the anti-slip extender to tighten
Try to adjust it as small as possible
Don't adjust too much at a time
If you adjust too much at a time
There will be a problem of breaking through the grid
In order to have a more detailed wrinkle effect
Please reduce the diameter to 10
Sometimes the scarf will spread
You can use a sewing needle to adjust the distance between the two points of the fabric
To tighten the scarf
After adding the sewing needle
The two ends will be sewed together
By adjusting the length of the line
It can not be unfolded or folded
More sewing needles can get better results
It has a better chance of slipping
I don't really like the sense of
In other words
The wind is too strong
I don't really like the sense of
In other words
The wind is too strong
I don't really like the sense of
That's all
Remember to read the process
to see if there is a crack
To see if there are any holes
Re-adjust
After adjustment, the shrink rate will be changed to 80%
Then select the fixed needle tool
On the top of the outside line of the plate in the 2D window
Double click can increase the fixed needle along this line
This can fix the position of a needle
Change the shrink rate to 110
The wrinkle will accumulate in this area
Then you can delete the fixed needle
It's more natural to simulate it again
If you don't think the effect of deleting the fixed needle is ideal
You can use the shape optimization
By using the shape optimization method
This plate will no longer deform
Maintain the current simulation form
When all the clothes are created on the plate
It is a triangular grid
You can use the reset grid function
Arrange the grid more neatly
You can see that due to the neat grid arrangement
The wrinkle of the fabric is also smoother
Triangular grid is a bit rough
But it has more texture
Here is a fine detail of the scarf
It is easy to see
That's all for the details of a scarf
You can try to make it
See you next time
Bye bye